Guide to the Ernie Paniccioli archive, [ca. 1960-2012]
Paniccioli, Ernie archive
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ernie Paniccioli archive, [ca. 1960-2012]
8079
Paniccioli, Ernie.
ca. 35 cubic feet.
Photographs, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographic prints, negatives, digital files, books, magazines, and other ephemera created or collected by Ernie Paniccioli representing the complete body of his work as an artist and photographer.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographic prints, negatives, digital files, books, magazines, and other ephemera created or collected by Ernie Paniccioli representing the complete body of his work as an artist and photographer from the 1960s to the present, including his work as a primary staff photographer for Word Up magazine. The archive includes ca. 35 cubic ft. of material comprised of more than 100,000 images in physical and digital form.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Paniccioli, Ernie.
Subjects:
Hip-hop -- History.; Hip hop; Hip-hop; Rap (Music); Hip-hop; Rap (Music)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; History; Periodicals; Pictorial works
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
By appointment only.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Magazine Clippings and Covers
Series II. Ephemera
Series III. Slides
Series IV. Photographs and Negatives
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Magazine Clippings and Covers
  - 2 Hype (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faces Rocks, Summer 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fly!, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hip Hop Connection, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hip Hop Weekly (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Murder Dog, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The New York Times Magazine, April 3, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - On The Go, December, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rap Masters, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Rap Pages, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Starline (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Source, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Source, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Source, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Source, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Source, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Source, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Source, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - VIBE (Box 1, Folder 16-19)
  - Word Up! (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 2, Folder 10-14)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous magazines and clippings (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
  - Clippings/ephemera (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, booklets and clippings (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Ernie Paniccioli folders with Paniccioli articles (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Flyers and photos in binder, loose material (Box 26)
  - Paniccioli clippings and tear sheets (Box 27, Folder 1-9)
  - 3 binders of clippings (Box 27)
- Series II. Ephemera
  - Clippings/ephemera (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Folders with ephemera (Box 3, Folder 3, 8)
  - Two rolled posters (Box 26)
  - Box of VIP passes and name tags (Box 27)
  - T-Shirts (Box 29-30)
  - Promotional hats (Box 31)
  - Large rolled posters and oversized clippings (Box 32)
- Series III. Slides
  - 8 Ball and MJG (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 3rd Bass (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 3rd Bass and others, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 50 Cent (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 112, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - 112, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 90210, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Aaliyah, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Afrika Bambaata, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Afrika Bambaata, 1991-2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Atlanta, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Avant, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - AZ (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - AZ, 1995-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - B2K (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - BB Mak, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Baby Cham, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Backstreet Boys, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Beenie Man, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Beenie Segal, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - BIG, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Big Pun, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - BIZ Markee (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Blaque, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  - Bobby Brown, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Bow Wow, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14, 20)
  - Boyz II Men, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Brandy, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Brandy, in binder, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Britney Spears, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Museum: Roots Rhymes and Rage exhibit, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Busta Rhymes, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cam'ron, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Canabus, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Capone N Noreaga, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Carl Thomas, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Case, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - CED (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Charli Baltimore, 4999 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Children's Choice Awards, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - City High (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Crucial Conflict, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cyppress Hill, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Da Brat, 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Das Efx, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - De La Soul, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dead Prez, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Deadly Venoms, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Debbie Cox (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Debbie Gibson (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Def Jam, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Digital Underground (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - DJ's, 1995-2003 (Box 5, Folder 9-11)
  - DJ Kool Herc, 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Doug E. Fresh, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - DMX, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dru Hill, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Ed and Dre, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - En Vogue, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - EPMD, 1992-1998 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Erykah Badu (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Eve, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Eve (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Faith, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Fashion Week, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Fashion Week book 2 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Fat Joe, 1994-2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Female artists, A-Z, in binders (Box 16)
  - Flash (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Flesh and Bones, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Fredro, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Fugees binder (Box 22)
  - Fushnikens, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Gangsta Boo, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Goodie Mob, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Graf slides binder (Box 22)
  - Graf and Punk slides and negatives binder (Box 22)
  - Hammer, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hanson (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hard Rock Tour, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Heavy D, 1992-? (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Heal (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
  - Hip Hop miscellany (Box 16)
  - Hip Hop Summit, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hot Boys, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Ice Cube, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Ice T (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Illegal, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 17-21)
  - Jade, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Jade, Lisa Lisa, 1994-2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Jamel Shabazz, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - James Brown, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Jason Priestly, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jay Z, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jermaine Dupri, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Jerry Riviera (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Jessica Simpson, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - JFK Jr., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Jimmy Scott (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Jingle Bell Ball: New Kids, Celine Dion, Aerosmith, Fiona Apple, Tom Petty, Jakob Dylan, Savage Garden, Sarah McLachlan, Backstreet Boys, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jodeci (Box 6, Folder 19-24)
  - Joe, Usher, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - John Forte, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - JT Money (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Kane (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Kid N Play (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - King Tee, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Kool G. Rap and Polo, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Kool Keith, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Kris Kross, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
  - KRS1, 1989-1999 (Box 7, Folder 12-16)
  - Kwame, Al B. Sure, Ascap, 1989-1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Latifah (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Latifah (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Latin Stars (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - L'il Ceas (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Lil Kim, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - L'il Zane, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - L'il Zane, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - LL Cool J, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 7-16)
  - Lord Tariq and Peter Gunn, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lords of the Underground, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lou Rawls Parade of Stars, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Lox (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Ludacris, 2000-2004 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Luke (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Lyte, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - Mac Mall, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Madd Rapper, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Malcolm X Stamp (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mary J. Blige, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Mase (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Memphis Bleek, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Method Man/Redman, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Michael Jackson, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous slides in loose sleeves (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous loose slides, slides in sleeves (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 31-39)
  - Miscellaneous in folders (Box 18, 19)
  - Miscellaneous A-P (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous I-L, Best of the Best (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous Q-Z, Best of the Best (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Best of the Best binder (Box 33)
  - Missy, Kim and Da Brat, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Montell Jordan, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Mop, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - My Room (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Mya, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Nas, 1996-2002 (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
  - Naughty (Box 9, Folder 15-25)
  - Naught (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Next, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - New Kids (Box 19)
  - New Music Seminar, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Nikki Dee (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Nonchalant, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Paris, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Prince (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Prodigy, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Puffy (Box 10, Folder 5-8)
  - Public Enemy (Box 10, Folder 9-18)
  - Public Enemy- Flavor Flav (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - QKumba Zoo, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - R. Kelly, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Rakim, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
  - Real Roxanne, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Redman, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Reggae dance hall artists (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Remy Martin, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ricky Martin, 1985-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Ricky Martin, with photographs (Box 21)
  - Rob Base, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Run DMC (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Special Ed (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Salt N' Pepa (Box 11, Folder 5-20)
  - Sinatra, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Sisters with a voice (Box 13, Folder 22-24)
  - Slick Rick (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Soul Jam (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Snoop, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Source Awards, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Sticky, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Stop the Violence (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Sweet Sensations (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Tim Dog (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - TLC, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Tommy Page, 1989-1998 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Tribe Called Quest, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - MC Trouble (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - U-God, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Usher, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - We'll always miss you big poppa, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Wedding- Busta Rhymes, Redman, Tyson (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Whodini, 1986-1994 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Who's the Man?, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Wu-Tang, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Wu-Tang, 1995-2001 (Box 12, Folder 16-19)
  - Wu Tang slides and photos (Box 33)
  - Wu Syndicate, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Wu-Tang - Shyheim, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - X-Clan, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - X-Scape (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
  - Xzhibit, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Zulu Conference, 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
- Series IV. Photographs and Negatives
  - Menudo album (Box 15)
  - Loose photos (Box 15)
  - Negatives, some slides, 1980s-1990s (Box 23, Folder 1-6)
  - Photographs with negatives in two boxes (Box 23)
  - Franco photo album (Box 24)
  - Red photo album, various artists (Box 24)
  - Studio shots album (Box 24)
  - Punk, Rastas, Street people album (Box 24)
  - Models and Street album (Box 24)
  - Graffiti album (Box 24)
  - Unlabelled green photo album (Box 24)
  - Menudo photo album (Box 24)
  - Binder of black and white photographs (Box 25)
  - Murals album (Box 25)
  - Franco and miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - Unlabelled black photo album, various artists (Box 25)
  - Miss Liberty album (Box 25)
  - Unlabelled binder, black and white photos (Box 25)
  - Black and white photo binder (Box 26)
  - Models (Box 26)
  - Nation of Islam loose photos (Box 27)
  - Nation of Islam photos (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - Photographs in red photo album (Box 33)